Guide to the Noël Riley Fitch Julia Child Papers MSS.323
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Noël Riley Fitch Personal Materials
  - El Bulli, 2004 - 2007 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Menu, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Audio
  This series consists primarily of audiocassettes of taped interviews conducted by Noël Riley Fitch in the course of research for Appetetite for Life, and also includes some material related to publicity of the book. These elements are arranged alphabetically then chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audio tapes have not been preserved and are not currently availble to researchers.
  - "Alison's Restaurant - Julia Child / Quest", 1980; ID: 323.0001; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0001)
  - "Julia Child, TV Cook Santa Barbara", 7/1/89; ID: 323.0002; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0002)
  - "Louise Bertholle", July 12, 1992; ID: 323.0003; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0003)
  - "Julia Child", December 5, 1992; ID: 323.0004; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0004, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0004)
  - "Katie Gates", April 24, 1993; ID: 323.0005; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0005)
  - "Dorothy Cousins", April 30, 1993; ID: 323.0006; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0006)
  - "Poly Group at Valley Hunt Club: Russell Lisle, Bishop Rhodes", June 31, 1993; ID: 323.0007; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0007)
  - "Gregory Usher", July 2, 1993; ID: 323.0008; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0008)
  - "John Mc Williams", August 13, 1993; ID: 323.0009; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0009)
  - "Paul Child's Twin Children - Rachel, Erica, Jonathan", August 17, 1993; ID: 323.0010; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0010)
  - "Mary Case Warner", November 3, 1993; ID: 323.0011; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0011)
  - "Julia Child", November 18, 1993; ID: 323.0012; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0012, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0012)
  - "Julia Child", November 21, 1993; ID: 323.0013; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0013, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0013)
  - "Dorothy Cousins and Mary Zook Beales", [1993]; ID: 323.0014; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0014)
  - "Dorothy and Sam Cousins", [1993]; ID: 323.0015; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0015)
  - "Women's History Month - Biographer [KDFK]", March 16, 1994; ID: 323.0016; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0016)
  - "Sally Miall", March 25, 1994; ID: 323.0017; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0017)
  - "Julia Child", April 13, 1994; ID: 323.0018; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0018, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0018)
  - "Robert Huttenback - Santa Barbara", May 7, 1994; ID: 323.0019; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0019)
  - "John Moore", May 20, 1994; ID: 323.0020; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0020)
  - "Pat and Herb Pratt", May 24, 1994; ID: 323.0021; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0021)
  - "Anita Hinckley Hoven", May 25, 1994; ID: 323.0022; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0022)
  - "Stephanie Herch - Julia's Assistant" [1 of 2], November 30, 1994; ID: 323.0023; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0023)
  - "Stephanie Herch - Julia's Assistant" [2 of 2], November 30, 1994; ID: 323.0024; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0024)
  - "Russ and Marian Morash" [1 of 2], December 14, 1994; ID: 323.0025; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0025)
  - "Russ and Marian Morash" [2 of 2], December 14, 1994; ID: 323.0026; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0026)
  - "Julia Child", December 16, 1994; ID: 323.0027; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0027, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0027)
  - "Ruth Lockwood", December 18, 1994; ID: 323.0028; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0028)
  - "Julia [Child]", March 1995; ID: 323.0029; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0029, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0029)
  - "William Truslow", April 20, 1995; ID: 323.0030; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0030)
  - "NPR Morning Edition: Julia Child Interview", [April - May] 1995; ID: 323.0031; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0031)
  - "Roads We've Traveled and Roads to Come: Clark Wolf interviews Julia Child, Chuck Williams, Joe Baum, Marion Cunningham, Judith Jones, Robert Mondavi" [A.I.W.F. Boston, MA], September 14 - 17, 1995; ID: 323.0032; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0032)
  - "Dorothy Cann Hamilton", December 14, 1995; ID: 323.0033; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0033)
  - "Dorothy Cann Hamilton", undated; ID: 323.0047; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0047)
  - "Richard Graff - San Francisco", February 2, 1996; ID: 323.0034; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0034)
  - "Julia Child Talk", April 16, 1996; ID: 323.0035; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0035)
  - "Jean Pool - Neighbor", April 19, 1996; ID: 323.0036; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0036)
  - "Clark Wolf", April 24, 1996; ID: 323.0037; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0037)
  - "Graham Kerr", April 25, 1996; ID: 323.0038; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0038)
  - "Jane Friedman", October 31, 1996; ID: 323.0039; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0039)
  - "Zane Early Stewart", November 15, 1996; ID: 323.0040; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0040)
  - "Noël Riley Fitch: Steve Knight's Broadcast Bistro KIEV 870 AM", 10/9/97; ID: 323.0041; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0041)
  - "Good Food: Mary Sue Milliken and Susan Feniger KCRW", 10/18/97; ID: 323.0042; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0042)
  - "Noël Riley Fitch: These Days with Dan [Erlwine] KPB Radio - San Diego, CA", 12/11/97; ID: 323.0043; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0043)
  - "Select Interview", 2003; ID: 323.0044; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0044)
  - "Select Staff [Bert, Francis, Didier]", June 13, 2005; ID: 323.0045; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0045)
  - "Biography: Portraits of the Artists - Moderator: Noël Fitch; T. Nolan, F. O'Toole, G. Robb, H. Spurling" - Los Angeles Times Festival of Books", undated; ID: 323.0046; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0046)
  - "E. Kennedy (Mother was Paul Child's Lover)", undated; ID: 323.0048; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0048)
  - "Julia Child C+D", undated; ID: 323.0049; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0049, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0049)
  - "Julia Child E / F", undated; ID: 323.0050; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0050, Box Digitized Access Copies, File fales_MSS323_0050)
  - "Lynne Rossette Kasper: [Talk about Julia]", undated; ID: 323.0051; Format: Microcassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0051)
  - "Pam Sheeline - (Nephew Paul & Sandra Sheeline)", undated; ID: 323.0052; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0052)
  - "Phila Cousins", undated; ID: 323.0053; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0053)
  - "Phila [Cousins]", undated; ID: 323.0054; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0054)
  - "Select Interview [1954] and Gregory Masurovsky", undated; ID: 323.0055; Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Media ID: 323.0055)
- Series VII: Video
  This series consists primarily of video of Julia Child interviews and cooking demonstrations, as well as some interviews with Noël Riley Fitch and other material related to the publicity of Appetite for Life. These elements are arranged chronologically then alphabetically.
  Videotapes have not been preserved and are not currently availble to researchers.
  - "KCBS - TV: Friday at Sunset in... Santa Barbara", 05 - 09 - 86; ID: 323.0056; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0056)
  - "Julia's Homecoming - An Evening with Julia Child at The Valley Hunt Club", November 7, 1990; ID: 323.0057; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0057)
  - "Julia Child Hall of Fame Segment", 1991; ID: 323.0058; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0058)
  - "Julia Child & French Chef Highlights", 1960s, March 1991; ID: 323.0059; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0059)
  - "Jula Child & Co - KCET, 1970s Repeats", August 22, 1992; ID: 323.0060; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0060)
  - "Merci Julia KPBS", March 4, 1993; ID: 323.0061; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0061)
  - "1993 Harvard Commencement: Morning Exercises", June 10, 1993; ID: 323.0062; Format: VHS TRT: [02:06:00] (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0062)
  - "Julia Child & Jacques Pépin: Cooking in Concert - KCET", August 1994; ID: 323.0063; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0063)
  - "Julia & Jacques", 1994; ID: 323.0064; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0064)
  - "TVFN: Dione Lucas #24 Crown Roast of Pork Chocolate Layer Cake", 10/28/96; ID: 323.0065; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0065)
  - "TVFN: James Beard #40 Chili Con Carne", 10/28/96; ID: 323.0066; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0066)
  - "TVFN: Julia Child "French Chef" #29 Souffle on a Platter", 10/28/96; ID: 323.0067; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0067)
  - "Julia Child & Jacques Pépin: More Cooking in Concert", 1996; ID: 323.0068; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0068)
  - "Noël Interviewed on Boise's NBC", September 1997; ID: 323.0069; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0069)
  - "Biography: Julia Child: An Appetite for Life" [Not Final, NRF not Credited], 1997; ID: 323.0070; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0070)
  - "Julia Child: Appetite for Life - An A&E Biography", 8/5/97; ID: 323.0071; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0071)
  - "Julia Child Guest Stars on Dessert Circles", 2/8/98; ID: 323.0072; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0072)
  - "10 Great Chefs - A&E Channel", June 10, 2000; ID: 323.0073; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0073)
  - "Julia Child's Kitchen Wisdom", 2000; ID: 323.0074; Format: VHS TRT: [01:28:00] (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0074)
  - "Julia Child's Kitchen Wisdom: Produced by A La Carte Communications", 2000; ID: 323.0075; Format: VHS TRT: [01:28:00] (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0075)
  - "America's French Chef: An Evening with Julia", August 19, 2002; ID: 323.0076; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0076)
  - "Copia: A Conversation with Julia Child", September 1, 2002; ID: 323.0077; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0077)
  - "Julia Bio", 2003; ID: 323.0078; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0078)
  - "Weller Grossman Productions: Noël Riley Fitch Interview (Food Network)", 12/21/07; ID: 323.0089; Format: DVD TRT: [02:00:00] (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0089)
  - "A Taste of Norway with Julia Child - Morash Productions", undated; ID: 323.0079; Format: VHS TRT: [00:57:37} (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0079)
  - "Julia #1", undated; ID: 323.0080; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0080)
  - "Dinner at Julia's, Show #101 - Salmon", undated; ID: 323.0081; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0081)
  - "Dinner at Julia's, Show #106", undated; ID: 323.0082; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0082)
  - "Julia Child and More Company, Show #204", undated; ID: 323.0083; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0083)
  - "Julia Child and More Company, Show #207", undated; ID: 323.0084; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0084)
  - "Last Video of Paul Child - Santa Barbara", undated; ID: 323.0085; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0085)
  - "In Kitchen with [Lagasse]", undated; ID: 323.0086; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0086)
  - "The Way to Cook First Courses and Desserts", undated; ID: 323.0087; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0087)
  - "The Way to Cook Vegetables", undated; ID: 323.0088; Format: VHS (Box 21, Media ID: 323.0088)
- Series VIII: Data Storage
  Data Storage disks have not been preserved and are not available to researchers.
  This series consists of computer disks including images and text files related to the production and publicity of Appetite for Life and the cafes books.
  - "Appetite for Life [Chapters] 1 - 15", undated; ID: 323.3.0001; Format: Imation 2HD Macintosh 3.5" Capacity: 1.40 MB (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0001)
  - "Appetite [Chapters] 16 - 27", undated; ID: 323.3.0002; Format: MF 2HD Maxell 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0002)
  - "Child Interviews", undated; ID: 323.3.0003; Format: Verbatim DataLife MF2 - HD 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0003)
  - "Front & End of Appetite for Life", undated; ID: 323.3.0004; Format: MF 2HD Maxell 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0004)
  - "Julia Child Book Business", 1995 - 1996; ID: 323.3.0005; Format: MF 2HD Maxell 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0005)
  - "Julia Child Notes", 12/16/96; ID: 323.3.0006; Format: Verbatim DataLife MF2 - HD 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0006)
  - "Julia Child Timeline", 11/96; ID: 323.3.0007; Format: Verbatim DataLife MF 2HD IBM 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0007)
  - "Noël's Interviews - Julia Child Book", undated; ID: 323.3.0008; Format: Maxell MF 2HD 3.5" Capacity: [unknown] (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0008)
  - "Le Select Interview", July 16, 2003; ID: 323.3.0009; Format: Imation 2HD IBM 3.5" Capacity: 1.44 MB (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0009)
  - "Café Central for Noël (Credit: Kimberley Sparks)", undated; ID: 323.3.0010; Format: CD-R Capacity: 80 Minutes / 700 MB (Box 22, Media ID: 323.3.0010)
- Series IX: Objects
  This series consists of a small amount of memorabilia, mostly clothing printed with logos related to various projects by Julia Child.
  - Providence Public Library Backstage Pass: A Conversation with Julia and Friends, May 1, 1998 (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0001)
  - A.I.W.F. Tote Bag, undated (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0002)
  - Radcliffe Culinary Friends Canvas Apron, undated (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0003)
  - The French Laundry Clothes Pin, undated (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0004)
  - In Julia's Kitchen with Master Chefs Blue Cap, undated (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0005)
  - Floral Apron with "Noel" Stitching, undated (Box 20, Object ID: 323.2.0006)
- OVERSIZE Series I: Appetite for Life: The Biography of Julia Child
  - Subseries E: Photographs and Images
    - Julia and Paul Child, 1956, 1966, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Kitchen Photograph by Brian Morris, July 1969 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Appetite for Life: Prints, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Blue Scrapbook I, 1990s (Box 24)
    - Red Scrapbook II, 1998 - 2004 (Box 25)
  - Subseries D: Publication, Publicity and Reception
    - Appetite for Life: Dust Jackets, Barnes and Noble Reading Sign, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Noël Riley Fitch Personal Materials
  - "Classical Restaurant Menus" [1 of 2], 2000 - 2003 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Classical Restaurant Menus" [2 of 2], 2003, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Restaurant Menus, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Menus [1 of 2], undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Menus [2 of 2], undated (Box 26, Folder 3)